Jonathan Brunt • Software Engineer

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/jonathan-m-brunt Phone: (405) 237-5614

Summary

A Software Engineer and Computer Scientist with success providing effective solutions for demanding business, education, technology, and customer requirements. Strengths include extensive knowledge of user interface and user experience, relational and non-relational databases, servers, networks, and hosting environments, including the implementation of this knowledge in an educational setting. A reputation for utilizing an extensive understanding of how to interact with teams, testing, quality assurance, and security concerns throughout the entire development lifecycle, while fulfilling business and educational needs.

Technology Skills

JavaScript • Python • C • React • Redux • Angular • Node • Express • SQL • MongoDB • Git/Version Control • HTML5 • CSS3 • SCSS • LESS • Styled Components • D3.js • Jest • Mocha • Chai • User Interface • User Experience • Testing • Servers • Networks • Hosting Environments • Adobe Creative Cloud • Various Remote Team Collaboration Tools

Professional Experience

<u>Tadah Tech</u> - Remote *Software Engineer* 11/2019-Present

Develop, maintain, and scale full-stack applications and websites while simultaneously managing the UI team and collaborating with the design team, management, and clients.

- Plan and build production applications and websites from inception through completion
- Technologies in use include JavaScript, React, Angular, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Java, Express, Node, and SQL
- Implement a custom system to ensure that performance, best practices, accessibility, SEO, and the standards of a Progressive Web Application are all prioritized, and that expectations are exceeded at all stages of development

<u>Lambda School</u> - Remote *Software Engineer, Teaching Assistant*

6/2018-11/2019 3/2019-11/2019

Delivered lectures to students daily, including theory and live coding, while they learned and utilized skillsets of computer science including data structures and algorithms, graphs, theory of computation, processes, and servers, with an emphasis on learning the Python and C languages.

- Led the implementation of the Teaching Assistant program in the Computer Science Department, as the first individual to serve in this position
- Within weeks of the position's implementation, student Sprint pass rates increased by 15% in the section
- Developed and revised course content in collaboration with instructors
- Selected and mentored new Teaching Assistants

Software Engineer, Master Based Progression Supervisor

9/2018-3/2019

Intensely mentored and supervised students beneath SP80 passing standard while they remediated JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, LESS, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, and SQL skillsets.

• Planned and delivered one-on-one daily consultation with students including code reviews, technical and soft skills improvement, and workflow improvement, leading to 88% of students succeeding in remediation

Software Engineer, Section Supervisor

7/2018-9/2018

Managed six Project Managers, mentored and supervised 40+ students while they learned and utilized JavaScript, HTML, CSS, LESS, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, SQL, Python, Django, and C skillsets.

- Led the implementation of a Master Based Progression to support students' goals to reach SP80 status and progress to capstone project and graduation
- Planned and delivered one-on-one consultations with staff and students, improving the student passing rate from an initial 60%, to 98% reaching passing status at course didactic completion

Software Engineer, Project Manager

6/2018-7/2018

Managed, mentored, and graded students for skills including JavaScript, HTML, CSS, LESS, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, SQL, Python, Django, and C.

Results enabled 100% of group's six students to achieve a passing rate of 80%+ on weekly exams

BPM Marketing - Remote

8/2018-11/2018

Software Engineer

Hired on a temporary, part-time basis to develop, maintain, and scale a portfolio of full-stack websites and applications for clients by leading web and application development projects.

- Improved the user interface and user experience of multiple client sites
- Technologies used included JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, PHP, multiple Content Management Systems, ASP.NET, Digital Ocean, Amazon S3, Photoshop, Illustrator, and InDesign
- Scaled the server of a movie premiere website in production to reach 15 million consumers via email to promote the online release date, and simultaneously built out the front-end

<u>Independent Consultant</u> - Houston, TX / Remote

8/2017-8/2018

Web Developer

Executed multiple full stack development projects for independent clients.

<u>Independent Consultant</u> - Houston, TX / Remote

8/2007-7/2017

Biostatistician, Epidemiologist Consultant

Developed and applied skills needed to understand determinants of disease and improve health and utilized descriptive and analytic approaches to investigate the complex causes of major public health problems.

Education

University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston, TX

2006-2007

Public Health / Epidemiology / Biostatistics

University of Houston, Houston, TX

1998-2002

Biochemistry / Chemistry